Smit Patel

34 Bailey Crescent, Scarborough, Ontario, M1G 2P3 smitm.patel@mail.utoronto.ca 647-760-6530

Resume Profile

2nd year Computer Science student at the University of Toronto Scarborough, specializing in mobile app development. Capable of implementing UI/UX design thinking to the development process via interviewing users, testing prototypes and gathering feedback iteratively to facilitate continuous improvement. Skilled in developing user-friendly interfaces for android applications that possess a clean and intuitive user experience. Developed a calendar app in android with a team of 3 developers that includes a time tabling feature.

Key Competencies: Android (Strong)/Game play Development (Intermediate)/Communication (Strong)/Prototyping (Intermediate)/Testing (Strong)/ Ideation(Strong)

Education

Honours Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Toronto Scarborough

2017 - Present

- Specialist in Software Engineering Co-op, 2nd Year
- Received Entrance Scholarship (\$7500)

Personal Projects

Personal Website (smitpatel.net)

January 2018

- Performed thorough research in designing website to create desired product in which the website flowed perfectly, and navigation was easy.
- Developed a portfolio-based website which captures the highlights of my career.
- Created using HTML, CSS, PHP, and JavaScript.
- Improved designing and programming skills from this experience, learned more about UI designing on how to make a website flow better.

Android App (AgendaX)

June 2017

- Lead a team of 3 to build AgendaX app to help students organize school work to further improve out collaboration and technical skills.
- We focused on creating certain features such as GradeBook which keeps track of your grades, it contains features such as calculating weighted grade, desired grade etc. To-do list was another feature in which the student would input upcoming tests/assignments and would be notified about it days before it.
- Created a timetable feature for better UI and helped debug any other problems that occurred.
- The purpose of implementing a timetable feature was to make it easier for students to have their timetable with them on their mobile devices.

Robocode May 2017

• Programmed a robot in Java to defeat A.I robots and classmates. My algorithm was placed runner up in my high school.

- Performed debugging with intensive detailing until the robot did not perform the desired tasks assigned to it perfectly.
- Implemented several different algorithms to confuse enemy robot from picking up my strategy.

Pokémon Game January 2017

- Made a game from programming in Java with Ui/Ux to simulate a two-player battle game.
- The game was then tested heavily with different test cases, and it did not crash once, the game flowed well which was the expected and desired result.
- Implemented new algorithms to make gameplay more enjoyable.

Relevant Experience

Teacher Assistant

Leacock Summer Camp

June 2015 - July 2015

- Edited class videos, and taught photoshop software to students with no experience, all students at the end of summer were able to use the photoshop software seamlessly.
- Aided the teacher at work and suggested improvements that could be made to improve learning process via using technology.
- Coached children to enhance their literature through the usage of technology, further increasing my leadership and problem solving skills.

Extracurricular Activities

Technical Helper

September 2016 – December 2016

Robotics Team 188

- Drew sketches of robots developed strategies and implemented in real life. Increasing robot's efficiency by at least 5%.
- Drew potential robot designs in adobe photoshop to help younger students better understand essential parts.
- Develop strategies to score more points and analyze opponent's strategy.
- Worked in teams to solve certain problem which might arrive with the robot.